TRACY PHAM

Phone: 0415 152 503 Email: tracyp161@gmail.com City/ Town: Melbourne, Vic

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/tracyp161/
Portfolio: https://compassionate-ritchie-283757.netlify.app/

CAREER PROFILE

An accomplished and highly skilled Full Stack Developer with the willingness to go beyond the standard work commitments in designing, developing web applications and technology solutions that provide exceptional user interfaces which are scalable and integrate easily with existing systems. My goal is to become an IT professional in a company, where I can enjoy working and contribute to achieving business goals. My expertise is in Frontend Development, JavaScript Library (React.JS), Web API, CSS Preprocessors, and UI Frameworks. I have strong experience working with related technology in an agile team environment.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming Languages

JavaScript React.JS/Redux HTML5 CSS3/SASS PHP/Laravel Wordpress I am very confident in these programming languages which I have used to build multiple applications. Please refer to my portfolio for more information.

Web API

I have successfully integrated many different APIs into my applications and I am very confident in building the back-end use of Node JS, GraphQL, Express JS, MongoDB, and Mongoose, the complete MERN Stack to provide RESTful API.

CSS Frameworks

Besides mastering the CSS implementation, I have worked with many different CSS libraries such as Bootstrap, MaterializeCSS, ReactBootstrap, MaterialUI, Styled Components, Tailwind

Database

MS SQL Server MySQL NoSQL MongoDB

Git Version Control & Testing Tools

Github Bitbucket Jest (learning)

SYSTEMS & APPLICATIONS

- Used different communication tools like Slack, Zoom, Skype, Microsoft Team.
- Being able to use different operating systems including Microsoft Windows, macOS, Linux, and their terminals.
- Proven knowledge of different Financial Software, including Xero and many internal financial systems of different organisations.
- Highly skilled in Adobe Creative Suites such as Photoshop, Illustrator, Indesign, After Effect.

QUALIFICATIONS & CERTIFICATIONS

Course	Institute	Year Completed
Certificate of Professional Year	Navitas Professional	2018
Bachelor of Information Technology	Melbourne Polytechnic	2017
Bachelor of Business	La Trobe University	2014

CAREER SUMMARY

Name of organisation	Year - Year
Freelance	Mar 2019 - present
Skyline Builders & Developers	Nov 2019 - Dec 2021
The Nova Group	Mar 2019 - Sep 2021
Psych Press	Dec 2017 - April 2018
Computer Troubleshooter	Oct 2016 - Dec 2016
	Freelance Skyline Builders & Developers The Nova Group Psych Press

RELEVANT CAREER HISTORY

Personal Projects 2021 - present

As a passionate coding person, I often develop apps on my own to practice and improve my skills. Please find the whole list in my portfolio. Here are some highlighted ones.

Project 1: My Portfolio

• A static website built by React to list all of my projects. Since it does not have a back-end, I handled its contact form by EmailJs to send viewers' inquiries directly to my email.

Link: https://compassionate-ritchie-283757.netlify.app/

Project 2: Todo List Portal Web App

A todo list app built by MERN STACK

Link: https://ancient-castle-24713.herokuapp.com/

Project 3: Martin's Movies

 A Movie Reviewing Web App using React hooks, Redux State Management & API Integration from The Movie Database

Link: https://martinsmovies123456.netlify.app/

Project 4: Dev Connector Web App

A social network connecting all developers built from MERN STACK

Link: https://tranquil-anchorage-03799.herokuapp.com/

Various mini-projects: using all different kinds of React & JavaScript Web API:

React Calculator App: https://vibrant-kilby-468fa8.netlify.app/

- Loan Calculator: https://naughty-curie-b4c3dc.netlify.app/
- React Styled Components Landing Page: https://afternoon-sierra-77442.herokuapp.com/
- Contact Keeper: https://obscure-tundra-75378.herokuapp.com/login

Achievements

- Frequently practice my programming skills through practical examples.
- Stay focused on new technologies in the IT industry.

Web Developer The Nova Group Mar 2019 - Sep 2021

The Nova Group is a global media advertising agency providing digital strategy, tv & radio advertising . digital media, social listener platform, e-commerce web and mobile apps, CRM, content management, and customer experiences https://www.thenovagroup.com.au/

As a contract web developer, my role included building and improving features allocated by my team leader.

Responsibilities

Project 1:

- Building a mini full stack social network application allowing users to connect with each other using PHP MVC Framework
- Link: https://attitude.ferttil.com/

Project 2: This project is a web design and development application for trading services

- Successfully followed to build from provided Figma/Photoshop designs
- Add a informative content and functions to the website
- Link: https://kitcomarkets.com/

Achievements

- Successfully implement an application from start to finish, including all front-end, back-end, and deployment.
- Proficiently using Git and Github to code in a team with other team members.
- Strong understanding of the project management process and how to implement tasks in a development team.

- Enhancing my PHP skills significantly since I need to use different styles of MVC frameworks to work with different legacy codes.
- Responsible for working on a range of projects, designing appealing websites and interacting on a daily basis with clients and marketers.
- Developing front-end functionality of sites.
 - Produce both eCommerce and non-eCommerce creative layouts, contents and developments using CMS systems (**Wordpress & Magento**) for the use of clients.
 - Writing browser compliant HTML and Javascript.
 - Simultaneously managing several design projects. Contacting external webmasters to confirm links.
 - Provide guidance to team members on key issues.
- Responsive design, perform best practises for UI and UX. Especially in an eCommerce context.
- Implement SEO in regard to page performance.
- Maintain and manage websites including Wordpress & Magento Plugins, domain hostings, WHM configuration and DNS